export const questions = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "Which of the following is related to \"Melody\" in the same way as \"Delicious\" is related to \"Taste\"?",
    options: ["Memory", "Highness", "Voice", "Speak"],
      correctAnswer: "Voice"
  },
  {
      id: 2,
      question: "\"Electricity\" is related to  \"wire\" in the same way as  \"water\" is related to :",
      options: ["Bottle", "Jug", "River", "Pipe"],
      correctAnswer: "Pipe"
  },
  {
      id: 3,
      question: "Ocean: Water:: Glacier : ?",
      options: ["Refrigerator", "Ice", "Mountain", "Cave"],
      correctAnswer: "Ice"
  },
  {
      id: 4,
      question: " \"Locker\" is related to  \"Jewellary\" in the same way as  \"Godown\" is related to",
      options: ["Storage", "Grasim", "Garments", "Goods"],
      correctAnswer: "Goods"
  },
  {
      id: 5,
      question: "Distil is related to Whiskey in the same way as Brew is related to?",
      options: ["Ferment", "Gin", "Beer", "Sugar"],
      correctAnswer: "Beer"
  },
  {
      id: 6,
      question: "Look at this series: 7, 10, 8, 11, 9, 12, ... What number should come next?",
      options: ["7", "10", "12", "13"],
      correctAnswer: "10"
  },
  {
      id: 7,
      question: "Look at this series: 53, 53, 40, 40, 27, 27, ... What number should come next?",
      options: ["12", "14", "27", "53"],
      correctAnswer: "14"
  },
  {
      id: 8,
      question: "Embellishing the Truth occurs when a person adds fictitious details or exaggerates facts or true stories. Which situation below is the best example of Embellishing the Truth?",
      options: [
          "Isabel goes to the theatre, and the next day, she tells her coworkers she thought the play was excellent.",
          "The realtor describes the house, which is eleven blocks away from the ocean, as prime waterfront property.",
          "During the job interview, Fred, who has been teaching elementary school for ten years, describes himself as a very experienced teacher.",
          "The basketball coach says it is likely that only the most talented players will get a college scholarship."
      ],
      correctAnswer: "The realtor describes the house, which is eleven blocks away from the ocean, as prime waterfront property."
  },
  {
      id: 9,
      question: "Applying for Seasonal Employment occurs when a person requests to be considered for a job that is dependent on a particular season or time of year. Which situation below is the best example of Applying for Seasonal Employment?",
      options: [
          "The ski instructors at Top of the Peak Ski School work from December through March.",
          "Matthew prefers jobs that allow him to work outdoors.",
          "Lucinda makes an appointment with the beach resort restaurant manager to interview for the summer waitressing position that was advertised in the newspaper.",
          "Doug's ice cream shop stays open until 11 p.m. during the summer months."
      ],
      correctAnswer: "Lucinda makes an appointment with the beach resort restaurant manager to interview for the summer waitressing position that was advertised in the newspaper."
  },
  {
      id: 10,
      question: "An Informal Gathering occurs when a group of people get together in a casual, relaxed manner. Which situation below is the best example of an Informal Gathering?",
      options: [
          "The book club meets on the first Thursday evening of every month.",
          "After finding out about his promotion, Jeremy and a few coworkers decide to go out for a quick drink after work.",
          "Mary sends out 25 invitations for the bridal shower she is giving for her sister.",
          "Whenever she eats at the Mexican restaurant, Clara seems to run into Peter."
      ],
      correctAnswer: "After finding out about his promotion, Jeremy and a few coworkers decide to go out for a quick drink after work."
  },
  {
      id: 11,
      question: "Pointing to a photograph of a boy Suresh said, \"He is the son of the only son of my mother.\" How is Suresh related to that boy?",
      options: ["Brother", "Uncle", "Cousin", "Father"],
      correctAnswer: "Father"
  },
  {
      id: 12,
      question: "If A is the brother of B; B is the sister of C; and C is the father of D, how D is related to A?",
      options: ["Brother", "Sister", "Nephew", "Cannot be determined"],
      correctAnswer: "Cannot be determined"
  },
  {
      id: 13,
      question: "If A + B means A is the mother of B; A - B means A is the brother B; A % B means A is the father of B and A x B means A is the sister of B, which of the following shows that P is the maternal uncle of Q?",
      options: ["Q - N + M x P", "P + S x N - Q", "P - M + N x Q", "Q - S % P"],
      correctAnswer: "P - M + N x Q"
  },
  {
      id: 14,
      question: "Introducing a boy, a girl said, \"He is the son of the daughter of the father of my uncle.\" How is the boy related to the girl?",
      options: ["Brother", "Nephew", "Uncle", "Son-in-law"],
      correctAnswer: "Brother"
  },
  {
      id: 15,
      question: "If D is the brother of B, how B is related to C? To answer this question which of the statements is/are necessary? A. The son of D is the grandson of C. B. B is the sister of D.",
      options: ["Only 1", "Only 2", "Either 1 or 2", "1 and 2 both are required"],
      correctAnswer: "1 and 2 both are required"
  },
  {
      id: 16,
      question: "Statements: Some actors are singers. All the singers are dancers. Conclusions: A. Some actors are dancers. B. No singer is actor.",
      options: ["Only (1) conclusion follows", "Only (2) conclusion follows", "Either (1) or (2) follows", "Neither (1) nor (2) follows", "Both (1) and (2) follow"],
      correctAnswer: "Only (1) conclusion follows"
  },
  {
      id: 17,
      question: "Statements: All the harmoniums are instruments. All the instruments are flutes. Conclusions: A. All the flutes are instruments. B. All the harmoniums are flutes.",
      options: ["Only (1) conclusion follows", "Only (2) conclusion follows", "Either (1) or (2) follows", "Neither (1) nor (2) follows", "Both (1) and (2) follow"],
      correctAnswer: "Only (2) conclusion follows"
  },
  {
      id: 18,
      question: "Statements: Some mangoes are yellow. Some tixo are mangoes. Conclusions: A. Some mangoes are green. B. Tixo is a yellow.",
      options: ["Only (1) conclusion follows", "Only (2) conclusion follows", "Either (1) or (2) follows", "Neither (1) nor (2) follows", "Both (1) and (2) follow"],
      correctAnswer: "Neither (1) nor (2) follows"
  },
  {
      id: 19,
      question: "Statements: Some papers are pens. All the pencils are pens. Conclusions: A. Some pens are pencils. B. Some pens are papers.",
      options: ["Only (1) conclusion follows", "Only (2) conclusion follows", "Either (1) or (2) follows", "Neither (1) nor (2) follows", "Both (1) and (2) follow"],
      correctAnswer: "Both (1) and (2) follow"
  },
  {
      id: 20,
      question: "Statements: All cups are books. All books are shirts. Conclusions: A. Some cups are not shirts. B. Some shirts are cups.",
      options: ["Only (1) conclusion follows", "Only (2) conclusion follows", "Either (1) or (2) follows", "Neither (1) nor (2) follows", "Both (1) and (2) follow"],
      correctAnswer: "Only (2) conclusion follows"
  },
  {
      id: 21,
      question: "Each question has an underlined word followed by four answer choices. You will choose the word that is a necessary part of the underlined word. harvest",
      options: ["autumn", "stockpile", "tractor", "crop"],
      correctAnswer: "crop"
  },
  {
      id: 22,
      question: "Each question has an underlined word followed by four answer choices. You will choose the word that is a necessary part of the underlined word. language",
      options: ["tongue", "slang", "writing", "words"],
      correctAnswer: "words"
  },
  {
      id: 23,
      question: "Each question has an underlined word followed by four answer choices. You will choose the word that is a necessary part of the underlined word. school",
      options: ["student", "report card", "test", "learning"],
      correctAnswer: "student"
  },
  {
      id: 24,
      question: "Each question has an underlined word followed by four answer choices. You will choose the word that is a necessary part of the underlined word. book",
      options: ["fiction", "pages", "pictures", "learning"],
      correctAnswer: "pages"
  },
  {
      id: 25,
      question: "Each question has an underlined word followed by four answer choices. You will choose the word that is a necessary part of the underlined word. success",
      options: ["money", "family", "school", "hard work"],
      correctAnswer: "hard work"
  },
  {
      id: 26,
      question: "There are four answer choices for the following analogy question. Select the answer that best completes the analogy. Cup is to coffee as bowl is to",
      options: ["dish", "soup", "spoon", "food"],
      correctAnswer: "soup"
  },
  {
      id: 27,
      question: "Yard is to garage as island is to",
      options: ["water", "map", "car", "cave"],
      correctAnswer: "water"
  },
  {
      id: 28,
      question: "Exercise is to gym as eating is to",
      options: ["food", "dieting", "fitness", "restaurant"],
      correctAnswer: "restaurant"
  },
  {
      id: 29,
      question: "Tree is to ground as chimney is to",
      options: ["smoke", "brick", "house", "roof"],
      correctAnswer: "house"
  },
  {
      id: 30,
      question: "Oyster is to shell as banana is to",
      options: ["peel", "wafer", "apple", "skillet"],
      correctAnswer: "peel"
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    question: "The small child does whatever his father was done.",
    options: ["has done", "did", "does", "had done", "No correction required"],
    correctAnswer: "does"
  },
  {
      id: 32,
      question: "You need not come unless you want to.",
      options: ["You don't need to come unless you want to", "You come only when you want to", "You come unless you don't want to", "You needn't come until you don't want to", "No correction required"],
      correctAnswer: "You don't need to come unless you want to"
  },
  {
      id: 33,
      question: "There are not many men who are so famous that they are frequently referred to by their short names only",
      options: ["initials", "signatures", "pictures", "middle names", "No correction required"],
      correctAnswer: "initials"
  },
  {
      id: 34,
      question: "The man to who I sold my house was a cheat.",
      options: ["to whom I sell", "to who I sell", "who was sold to", "to whom I sold", "No correction required"],
      correctAnswer: "to whom I sold"
  },
  {
      id: 35,
      question: "He is too important for tolerating any delay.",
      options: ["to tolerate", "to tolerating", "at tolerating", "with tolerating", "No correction required"],
      correctAnswer: "to tolerate"
  },
  {
      id: 36,
      question: "Statements: A. The prices of petrol and diesel in the domestic market have remained unchanged for the past few months. B. The crude oil prices in the international market have gone up substantially in the last few months.",
      options: ["Statement I is the cause and statement II is its effect", "Statement II is the cause and statement I is its effect", "Both the statements I and II are independent causes", "Both the statements I and II are effects of independent causes", "Both the statements I and II are effects of some common cause"],
      correctAnswer: "Both the statements I and II are effects of independent causes"
  },
  {
      id: 37,
      question: "Statements: A. The government has recently fixed the fees for professional courses offered by the unaided institutions which are much lower than the fees charged last year. B. The parents of the aspiring students launched a severe agitation last year protesting against the high fees charged by the unaided institutions.",
      options: ["Statement I is the cause and statement II is its effect", "Statement II is the cause and statement I is its effect", "Both the statements I and II are independent causes", "Both the statements I and II are effects of independent causes", "Both the statements I and II are effects of some common cause"],
      correctAnswer: "Statement II is the cause and statement I is its effect"
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    question: "Statements: A. The Reserve Bank of India has recently put restrictions on few small banks in the country. B. The small banks in the private and co-operative sector in India are not in a position to withstand the competitions of the bigger in the public sector.",
    options: [
      "Statement I is the cause and statement II is its effect",
      "Statement II is the cause and statement I is its effect",
      "Both the statements I and II are independent causes",
      "Both the statements I and II are effects of independent causes",
      "Both the statements I and II are effects of some common cause"
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Statement II is the cause and statement I is its effect"
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    question: "Statements: A. India has surpassed the value of tea exports this year over all the earlier years due to an increase in demand for quality tea in the European market. B. There is an increase in demand of coffee in the domestic market during the last two years.",
    options: [
      "Statement I is the cause and statement II is its effect",
      "Statement II is the cause and statement I is its effect",
      "Both the statements I and II are independent causes",
      "Both the statements I and II are effects of independent causes",
      "Both the statements I and II are effects of some common cause"
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Both the statements I and II are independent causes"
  },
  {
    id: 40,
    question: "Statements: A. There is unprecedented increase in the number of young unemployed in comparison to the previous year. B. A large number of candidates submitted applications against an advertisement for the post of manager issued by a bank.",
    options: [
      "Statement I is the cause and statement II is its effect",
      "Statement II is the cause and statement I is its effect",
      "Both the statements I and II are independent causes",
      "Both the statements I and II are effects of independent causes",
      "Both the statements I and II are effects of some common cause"
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Both the statements I and II are effects of independent causes"
  },
  {
    id: 41,
    question: "SCD, TEF, UGH, ____, WKL",
    options: ["CMN", "UJI", "VIJ", "IJT"],
    correctAnswer: "VIJ"
  },
  {
    id: 42,
    question: "FAG, GAF, HAI, IAH, ____",
    options: ["JAK", "HAL", "HAK", "JAI"],
    correctAnswer: "JAK"
  },
  {
    id: 43,
    question: "QAR, RAS, SAT, TAU, _____",
    options: ["UAV", "UAT", "TAS", "TAT"],
    correctAnswer: "UAV"
  },
  {
    id: 44,
    question: "DEF, DEF2, DE2F2, _____, D2E2F3",
    options: ["DEF3", "D3EF3", "D2E3F", "D2E2F2"],
    correctAnswer: "D2E2F2"
  },
  {
    id: 45,
    question: "QPO, NML, KJI, _____, EDC",
    options: ["HGF", "CAB", "JKL", "GHI"],
    correctAnswer: "HGF"
  }
];